Kabuto Yakushi
（イタチ）自分が何者か
知りたければ→
If you want to know who you are…
本当の自分を見つめ直し
認めることだ。
You must re-examine and
acknowledge your true self.
己自身を認めてやることが
できないやつは　失敗する。
Those who cannot acknowledge
themselves will fail…
かつての俺のようにな。
Just like I did.
（カブト）最初から
僕は　何者でもなかった。
I was nobody…
僕には　何もない。
and had nothing
from the very beginning.
（ノノウ）カブト　まだいける？
はい　マザー。
Kabuto, are you able
to keep going?
Yes, Mother!
（ウルシ）院のためとはいえ
なんで　忍相手に俺たちまで。
I know it's for the sake
of the orphanage,
but why do we have
to help shinobi like them?
何もしないで
お金は発生しないからだよ。
Doing nothing doesn't
bring in money…
ウルシは　包帯とってきてくれる？
あいよっと。
Urushi, could you get more bandages?
Yeah, sure!
（大蛇丸）忍でもないのに
いい腕ね　その医療忍術。
You're not a shinobi,
but you're quite skilled
at Medical Ninjutsu…
マザーに教えてもらったんです。
Mother taught me.
カブトとかいったわね。
You said your name was Kabuto?
キミ　忍になれば？
Why don't you become a shinobi?
いい忍になるわよ　きっとね。
You'd make a good one…
I'm sure of it.
僕は　そんなつもりないです。
I'm not interested in that.
こうやって　少しでも
孤児院にお金を貯めて→
I just want to help raise money
for the orphanage
ずっと　そこでマザーのお手伝いが
したいだけですから。
and help Mother there.
いろいろしてもらったのに→
She's done so much for me…
まだ　メガネくらいしか
プレゼントしてあげられてないし。
but I've only been able to repay her
with a pair of eyeglasses…
そう…　もったいないわね。
Really? What a shame.
（ダンゾウ）あの歩きの巫女と
呼ばれたお前が→
You were known
as the Wandering Nun,
今や　子守とはな。
and now you're just a babysitter.
（ダンゾウ）久方ぶりに　こうして見ると
少しやつれたか　ノノウ。
It's been a while
since I last saw you,
but you're looking a little tired, Nonou.
それは　とうに捨てた名です。
I cast aside that name long ago.
すでに　木ノ葉の里との
援助金の話は　カタがついたはず。
Talks with the Leaf for
monetary aid were concluded.
なぜ　今になって。
So why are you here now?
It seems the Espionage Unit's
former top spy
諜報部一　エリートだったお前が→
根を離れた途端
何も知らなくなったか。
stopped knowing things after
she left the Foundation.
援助金だけの話で
来たのではない。
We did not come here only
in regard to the aid money.
この戦時において→
In this time of war,
岩隠れが　大規模な作戦を
企んでいるという情報を入手した。
we have obtained intel that
the Hidden Stone are plotting
some sort of large-scale operation.
その情報が正しいか→
We want you to infiltrate
the Hidden Stone
お前に岩隠れの里に潜入して
調べてもらいたい。
and verify the validity of this intel.
そして　それが
正しかった場合→
And if it does turn out to be true,
その作戦が　いつどこで行われ
どんな作戦内容なのかも調べ→
you are to investigate what
this operation entails
and where it will occur
and report back to us.
こちらに
報告していただきたい。
恐らく　長期任務となる。
This will likely be
a long-term mission.
なら　お門違いです。
私はもう…。
Then you've come
to the wrong person.
I'm no longer…
あんたたちは　わかっていない！
You people don't understand
just how essential Mother is
マザーの存在が
この院と子供たちにとって→
to this orphanage and
to the children!
どれほど大切か！
マザーは　必死にやりくりし
この院を守ってきた。
She has done her utmost
to protect this orphanage.
そんな危ない任務→
Such a dangerous task!
You Foundation people ought
to do it yourselves.
根のあんたたちが
やったらいいでしょうが！
なぜ　わざわざマザーにまで。
Why must you come
and bother her?
The Wandering Nun is the only one
この長期任務を
任せられるのは→
歩きの巫女をおいて他にない。
we can entrust
this long-term mission to.
今の根に　こやつ以上の
諜報活動ができる者は→
Currently, no one in the Foundation
has her espionage skills.
ひとりとしておらぬ。
たいがいの者は
心を壊すか敵に寝返る。
Most would likely break or
end up switching allegiances.
こやつが　木ノ葉を売るような
くのいちでないことは知っている。
I know that she's a Kunoichi
who would never sell out
the Hidden Leaf…
その顔　すでに
察しがついているな。
From that expression,
I can tell you've already
guessed it, Nonou.
ノノウよ　そうだ　これを断れば
今後　院にカネは入らん。
Yes, if you refuse,
this clinic will stop receiving funding.
そんな！　ちゃんと三代目
火影様との話もついてんのよ！
That's not fair!
This was already settled
with the Third Hokage!
そんなことが
許されるわけないでしょう！
You cannot do this!
This orphanage looks easy
to break into and rob…
この院は　ずいぶん
泥棒が入りやすそうだな。
カネを盗まれぬよう
用心棒を雇うことを勧めておく。
You should hire bodyguards
to prevent robbers
from stealing your money.
もっとも　カネがあればの話だが。
That is, if you can afford any.
ついでに　子供たちまで
盗まれぬよう　用心することね。
While you're at it,
take care that your children
don't get snatched either.
身元のわからぬ子供は
何かと利用価値があるから…。
Children with no past or family
are worth something.
お前ら汚いぞ！　それでも忍か！？
You're all rotten!
How dare you call
yourselves shinobi?!
わかってないのは
そちらのほうだ！
You're the ones
who don't understand!
（２人）あっ…。
木ノ葉を守るためなら
安いものだ。
It's a small price to pay
to protect the Hidden Leaf!
わかりました。
ちょっと　マザー！
I understand.
Wait, Mother…!
心を殺しきれぬ　お前だからこそ
こうなったのだ。
It's come to this because
you couldn't kill your emotions.
やはりお前は　根には向かぬ。
You weren't suited for
the Foundation, after all.
よくも　ぬけぬけと…。
How dare you…!
それと　今回の情報を
入手するために→
Also, I've already lost a subordinate
obtaining this intel…
わしの部下が１人死んだ。
代わりに　ここの子供を
１人いただいていく。
I'll be taking one of the children here
to take his place.
どこまで！
私は依頼を受けると言ったはず！
How far will you go?
I said I'd accept the mission!
それとこれとは別だ。
This is a separate matter.
Your mission shall cover
subsequent payments.
次回からのカネは用立ててやる。
だが　今回の分は
その１人と交換だ。
But this current one is
in exchange for the child.
何より　子供のほうから
木ノ葉の忍になりたいと→
Some children actually wish to
become a Leaf Shinobi, after all.
申し出る場合も
ないわけではない。
尋ねてみるといい。
You should ask them
to choose for themselves.
（ダンゾウ）１人くらいは
いるかもしれぬからな。
There may just be one such child.
カブト　どうして…。
Why, Kabuto?
僕は忍者に向いている。
I think I'm suited to be a ninja.
医療忍術も究めたいしね。
Besides, I want to hone
my Medical Ninjutsu.
カブト！
俺らとの３年間を捨てんのか！？
Kabuto! You're just going to throw away
the three years you spent with us?!
（ウルシ）こっちへ来いよ！
Come back here!
みんな　院でのルールを忘れたのか？
Have you forgotten
the house rules, everyone?
（カブト）もう　とっくに寝る時間だよ。
It's way past lights-out.
ハァ　ハァ　ハァ…。
《ダメだ…　囲まれてる…》
It's no use. I'm surrounded.
《ヘマをしなければ→
If I hadn't messed up,
I'd be in bed by now.
もう　とっくに
寝てる時間だったのに。
院を出て　５年か…。
It's been five years since
I left the orphanage.
もう一度　マザーやみんなに
会いたかったな》
I wish I could've seen Mother and
everyone else one last time…
Mother!
マザー！！
No! Why are you here?
そんな…
なんでこんなところに！？
((お前に岩隠れの里に潜入して
調べてもらいたい。
We want you to infiltrate
the Hidden Stone…
この長期任務を任せられるのは→
The Wandering Nun is the only one
(歩きの巫女をおいて　他にない))
we can entrust this
long-term mission to.
《まさか…　まだあのときの
任務を続けてたのか？》
Don't tell me…you were still
on that last mission?!
なぜ…　私の傷を…。
Why are you healing my wounds?
あなたは　いったい…？
Who are you…?
僕だよ　マザー。
It's me, Mother!
カブトだよ。
It's Kabuto!
Don't worry, I'll save you.
心配しないで…　必ず助ける！
誰…　なの？
Who…are you…?
（黄ツチ）こっちだ！
This way!
クソ！　ナニガシが　やられた。
Damn it! Nanigashi's been killed!
《マザーは僕のことを…　なぜ？
Mother didn't know me? Why?
なぜ　僕のことを覚えていない…？
Why didn't she remember me?
Why?
どうして…。
だとしたら
今まで　僕はなんだったんだ…。
If she doesn't remember me,
then who was I all this time?
マザーから　もらったものは
なんだったんだ…。
What were all those things
I received from Mother?
名前も　マザーの子供であることも…。
My name, that I was
one of Mother's children,
このメガネさえも…》
even these glasses…
これは…　誰だ…。
Who…
are you?
これは　僕じゃない…。
This isn't me…
本当の僕じゃない…。
This isn't the real me…
自分が
はっきり見えていないようね。
It seems you no longer
see yourself clearly.
いい忍になったじゃない…。
You've become a fine shinobi.
私は覚えてるわよ…　カブト。
I remember you…Kabuto.
あなたは　たしか…。
A-Aren't you…?!
キミのことを　ずっと
監視させてもらってたのよ。
I've been watching you
this whole time.
ノノウも　一緒に。
Along with Nonou.
私に　ついてきなさい。
Come with me.
そしたら　あなたの知りたいことを
教えてあげる。
Then I'll tell you everything
you want to know.
知りたいこと…　何をです！？
What I want to know?
What does that mean?
なぜ　マザーがあなたを狙い…。
Why Mother targeted you…
そして
あなたを覚えていなかったのか。
and why she didn't
remember you at all.
知りたくはないの？　それを…。
Don't you want to know…all that?
ここは　私のアジト…。
誰も知らない。
This is my hideout.
No one knows about it.
つまり　あなたが初めての客。
Which means you are
my very first visitor.
なぜ　わざわざ　こんな所へ！？
どうする気なんです！
Why did you bring me here?!
What are you going to do with me?
あなた…　知りたいことが
どんどん増えるわね。
You are becoming
more and more curious.
それは　いいことよ。
That's a good thing.
人は　知りたいという欲望から
逃れられない…。
People can never escape
their curiosity.
だから　あなたは　こうして
ここへ　ついてきた。
Which is why you followed me here.
なら　さっさと教えてください！
Then tell me quickly!
あなたは　僕の知りたいことを
知ってるんでしょう！？
You know what I want to know,
don't you?
率直に言うとね→
To be frank, the Foundation
had decided
根は　あなたもマザーも
処理することに決めてたのよ。
to dispose of both you and Mother.
どういうことです！？
What do you mean?!
あなたたちは
スパイとして優秀すぎた…。
You both were too brilliant
as spies.
いろいろと　知りすぎたからよ。
そんな…。
You ended up knowing too much.
What?!
里のために長い間　命がけで
情報を集めさせておいて→
We risked our lives for so long,
gathering intel for
the sake of the village…
今さら…？
情報は　時として→
And this is what we get?
At times, intel becomes
even more powerful
強力な術や武器より
強い力を持つことになる…。
than the mightiest jutsu or weapon.
いまや　キミは
危険人物と見なされてるのよ。
You are seen as a very dangerous
person right now.
キミたちが　いずれ
こうなることは→
Well, your fate had been decided
from the very beginning…
はじめから
決められていたんだけど…。
更には→
It was in the scenario
２人共倒れを狙うことも
シナリオのうち…。
for you to kill each other in
a mutual strike.
キミが院を出て　すぐあと→
Right after you left the orphanage,
ダンゾウは　マザーに→
Danzo revealed to Mother
the real reason why you had left.
キミが院を出た
本当の理由を話したのよ。
院へのお金のために
キミは犠牲となって　根に入ったと。
That you sacrificed yourself
and joined the Foundation
for money for the orphanage.
マザーは　キミを
根から解放することを願った。
Mother wished to liberate you
from the Foundation.
ダンゾウは　その願いを
受け入れる条件として→
As a condition of accepting her wish,
Danzo ordered the assassination
数年前に　ある男を
暗殺するよう命令した。
of a certain person
several years ago.
おかしな話だけど→
Ironically…
その暗殺ターゲットの男こそ
キミだったのよ。
The target of the assassination…
was you.
僕を解放するための
条件じゃなかったの？
I thought it was the condition
for my release!
なぜ　マザーは
僕だと気づかなかったんだ！
Why didn't Mother realize
it was me?!
言ったでしょ。
I told you…
初めから根は　キミたちの
共倒れを狙っていたって。
The Foundation intended
for the two of you
to take each other out.
そこにも　カラクリがあるのよ。
And there was other trickery afoot.
カラクリ…。
Trickery?
キミとマザーが会わないよう
２人の潜入敵地を離し→
You and Mother were sent into
separate enemy territories
so that you two would never meet,
マザーには　キミの安否を→
and Mother was kept informed
of your well-being
キミの成長過程の写真で
知らせていた。
and progress through photos.
その写真が途中から→
The photos of you
were skillfully replaced
うまく別人と
すげ替えられてるとも知らず→
with those of another
without her noticing it.
長い時間をかけて　他人をキミだと
すり込まされていたのよ。
Over time, Mother was made
to think someone else was you.
時間をかけた洗脳。
Gradual brainwashing.
根の常套手段のひとつ。
A common practice used
by the Foundation.
そいつが　もう一人のカブト。
That's the other Kabuto.
だから　キミを
カブトだとは夢にも思わず→
And so, Nonou tried to kill you,
ノノウは　キミを殺そうとした。
never in her wildest dreams
imagining that you were Kabuto…
里に仇なす
裏切り者の二重スパイとしてね。
She thought you were a double agent
who betrayed the village.
そして　あなたが→
And the Foundation dispatched you
to deal with whoever was left…
生き残ったほうを始末するために
根より遣わされた忍。
そういうことですか。
Is that it?
自分のことは
まるでわかってないのに→
For someone who knows
nothing about himself…
よくわかってるじゃない。
You're very perceptive.
僕を　説明できるものが
ずっと欲しかった。
I always wanted…
an explanation about who I was!
やっと手に入ったと思ったのに
根のお前らのせいで→
And I thought
I had finally found it!
But thanks to you
Foundation bastards,
僕はまた
何者かわからなくなった。
I've lost myself again!
メガネは　僕とマザーを
つなげるものだったのに。
These glasses were
what linked me to Mother!
もらった名は
僕だけのものだったのに。
The name she gave me
was mine and mine alone!
何があっても
僕の姿を忘れない親が→
Mother was supposed
to be the parent
that didn't forget me,
no matter what!
マザーのはずだったのに！
すべて違うじゃないか！
But everything's wrong!
なら　僕はいったい　何だ！？
Then who in the world…
am I?!
ハァ　ハァ…。
うわっ！
キミは自分を説明できるだけの
情報が足りないだけ。
You merely lack sufficient intel
with which to define yourself.
メガネも名も　子供であることも→
It's just that neither the glasses,
your name,
nor the fact that you're her child
本当の自分を
示すものではなかった。
were things that denote
who you really are.
それでいいじゃない。
And that's fine.
今までのものが
納得できないなら→
If you're not satisfied with
what you've had so far…
代わりのものを見つけて→
Just find other things and
add them onto yourself,
次々に足していけば
いいだけのこと。
one by one.
僕を殺すつもりなら
なぜ僕に　そんなことを話す！？
If you plan on killing me…
why are you telling me all this?
私も自分が
何者なのかを知りたくてね。
I also want to know who or what I am.
あらゆるものを集めているの。
And I've been collecting
all sorts of things.
少しずつ集めた多くのものから
実験と検証を繰り返し→
I repeatedly experiment on
and inspect these many things
I've collected a little at a time…
知識と能力を
己に蓄積させてゆく。
and store the gained knowledge
and abilities within myself.
そして　そこから
新しい完璧な自分に向かって→
And then, I undergo rebirth,
生まれ変わっていく。
ever evolving toward
a more perfect me.
そしてまた　同じように
新しいものを手に入れる。
Afterward, I again obtain
even newer items.
今回は…　キミよ。
This time…
it's you.
自分が何者かだって
この世のあらゆるものと情報→
There's no way you couldn't derive
who you are and what you are
それらすべてを
集めつくしさえすれば→
by gathering all the intel and
things that exist in this world.
導き出せないはずはないのよ。
なぜ　あなたにとって
僕が　そのひとつなんだ？
Why am I one of those things
to you?
私は　キミの才能を
誰よりも買ってるからよ。
Because I recognize your talent
more than anyone else
in this world.
殺すなんて　もったいない。
It would be a waste to kill you.
それに　ここは
キミのために用意した医療実験施設。
Besides, this medical research facility
was prepared just for you.
何を企んでる？
What are you plotting?
己を消す根とは違い→
Instead of the Foundation
which erases individuality…
己を導き出す組織　里を作る。
I will create an organization
that guides individuality.
I will create a village.
どの国にも属さない　音隠れの里。
The Village of the Hidden Sound…
that does not belong to any nation.
私とキミは
今より　木ノ葉の根を抜ける。
From this moment,
you and I will desert
the Hidden Leaf's Foundation.
そして　今より
私が　キミの上司となり→
From this moment,
I shall be your superior,
your brother, and your parent.
兄弟となり　親となる。
私が　ダンゾウから　あなたを守る。
I will protect you from Danzo.
これより
あなたの新しい経歴は　こう。
From this moment,
this will be your
new personal history:
キミは　幼少のころ
桔梗峠の戦いにおいて→
When you were very young,
you were found and raised
by a Medical Corps Captain
following the Battle at Kikyo Pass.
医療部隊長に
拾われて育てられる。
ダンゾウのもとに戻って以降→
After returning to work under Danzo,
Nonou Yakushi kept her cover
as a captain of the Medical Unit…
表の顔として　医療部隊長となった
薬師ノノウの子としてね。
キミは　今日より新たに→
and you shall be reborn today
as her son, Kabuto Yakushi.
薬師カブトとして生まれ変わるのよ。
私は　大蛇丸。
自分が何者か知りたいのなら
さぁ　私の傍らへ。
次に調べたいと思っている
組織があるのよ。
（カブト）お任せください。
で　その組織とは？
暁。
（サソリ）大蛇丸の人体実験データと→
穢土転生についての
情報を持ってこい。
承知いたしました。　サソリ様。
お前は使える。
音を消し　匂いを消し　己を消す。
まるで　俺の傀儡のようだ。
《今までのものが
納得できないなら→
代わりのものを見つけて→
次々に足していけば
いいだけのこと。
（カブト）うわぁ～！
まだ…　まだ足りない…。
これは　まだ僕じゃない！
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手→